# **Neel Bhasin**

# Mobile Application Developer

+91-9818668018 | neelb2@gmail.com | Gurugram, India

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Mobile application engineer with 9+ years' experience in multiple product domains. Always eager to learn and grow my knowledge to build a career that helps me explore and challenge my potential and achieve my and organization's goals.

# **TECH STACK**

Front End	Swift, iOS, JavaScript, React Native, Android(Beginner), SwiftUI, Objective-C
Back End	Java, C#.Net, GraphQL
Data Stores	MySQL
CI/CD	Jenkins, Github Actions, FastLane, BitRise
Architecture	MVC. MVVM, Clean Architecture,
Frameworks	Combine, RxSwift

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Software Developer | Dhani | Gurugram, India

Jan, 2022 - Till Date

Dhani is a fin-tech platform based in India that makes digital payments on the go. It has bill payments, stock trading, daily needs and pharmacy delivery supported across India.

- Working on Dhani Mobile App as Technical lead
- Also take care day to day development and release process.
- Identifying and fixing customer facing issues with quick resolution.
- Following extensive Unit Testable approach with TDD.
- Technologies: Swift, Objective-C, SwiftUI, Combine
- Architecture MVVM and Clean Architecture

DreamSports is a leading sports platform based in India that allows users to play fantasy cricket, hockey, football, kabaddi and basketball. It also provides Live Scores, Live Video Streaming through Fancode App. In April 2019, Dream11 became the first Indian gaming company to enter the 'Unicorn Club'. Also Fancode App lists in Top 10 sports apps in India.

- Working on Fancode, a sports content and live streaming app.
- Working as a software developer with day to day development and release lead.
- Identifying and fixing customer facing issues with quick resolution.
- Following extensive Unit Testable approach with TDD.
- Technologies: Swift, Objective-C, React Native, Typescript, GraphQL
- Architecture Clean Architecture with Interactor

#### Senior Mobile Developer| Birdeye | Gurugram, India

May, 2018 to Dec, 2018

BirdEye is the all-in-one customer experience software: Online Reviews, Social, Surveys, Insights, Reputation.

- Worked on BirdEye iOS App
- Developed and maintained iOS Apps for the company. Also developed the Chat SDK.
- Managed the iOS team and led the new initiatives.
- Working closely with the product management team to solve customers problems.
- <u>Technologies</u>: Swift, Objective-C, RxSwift

#### Senior iOS Developer | SmartWorks | Gurugram, India

Mar, 2017 to Apr, 2018

SmartWorks is Co-working business center and commercial real estate company

- Worked on Smartworks iOS App, VMS iPad App
- Developed and maintained iOS Apps for the company.
- Managed the iOS team and led the new initiatives.
- Day to day task assignment to team members and coordination with the product management team
- <u>Technologies</u>: Swift, Objective-C

## Senior Software Engineer (Mobile App) | Snapdeal | Delhi, India

July, 2014 to March, 2017

Snapdeal is an Indian e-commerce company based in New Delhi, India. As of 2014, Snapdeal had 3,00,000 sellers, over 3 crore (30 million) products across 800+ diverse categories from over 1,25,000 regional, national, and international brands and retailers and a reach of 4,000 towns and cities across the country.

- Worked on Snapdeal iOS App, Windows Phone App
- Handling tasks with complete ownership.
- New feature development on iOS. Code and Platform level Design.
- Adding new features as required to the Snapdeal Windows Phone App.
- Code refactoring and development of new features as well.
- Delivered and leading project till release.
- Web development in payment gateway unit of Snapdeal

- Integration of the payment gateway to the Client's Website.
- Technologies: Objective-C, Swift, C#

#### Software Developer | PC Smart Care | Delhi, India

June, 2013 to July 2014

PC Smart Care is a KPO and solution provider for Software and Technical support

- Worked on PC Smart Cleaner, CRM (ASP.NET Based), Web Portal
- Develop and maintain new software applications.
- Worked on design and development of the websites
- Integrated payment gateway on the website
- <u>Technologies</u>: C#, ASP.net, WPF, Javascript

#### Software Developer | Micropack Industrial Instruments | Meerut, India

June, 2012 to June 2013

Micropack Industrial Instruments is a industrial automation and solution provider

- Worked on Vehicle Tracking System
- Develop software applications.
- Took part in learning new technologies.
- <u>Technologies</u>: C#, ASP.net, Javascript, MySQL

# **EDUCATION**

B.Tech(Computer Science) | MaharshiDayanand University | Rohtak (Haryana), India

2008-2012

#### **PROFILES**

Personal Website: <a href="http://neelbhasin.com/">http://neelbhasin.com/</a> LinkedIn: <a href="https://in.linkedin.com/in/neelbhasin">https://in.linkedin.com/in/neelbhasin</a>

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/neelb2">https://twitter.com/neelb2</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/neelb2">https://github.com/neelb2</a>

StackOverflow: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/1931578/neel-bhasin">https://stackoverflow.com/users/1931578/neel-bhasin</a>